"生活大爆炸" 前情提要...
Previously on The Big Bang Theory...
Sheldon 你是找出了
Sheldon, did you just figure out
人工合成新的稳定超重元素的方法了吗?
a method for synthesizing a new stable super-heavy element?
是吗?
Did I?!
这不对劲
Well, that can't be right.
以前都没人做到的
No one's ever done that before.
除了我 因为我算出来了!
Except me because I just did it!
# Sheldon的脑子最管用 耶 #
# Sheldon and his brain, yeah #
# Sheldon的脑子最管用 耶! #
# Sheldon and his brain, yeah! #
我犯了一个天大的错误
I've made a horrible mistake.
你在说什么呢?
What are you talking about?
这个周期表... 它的单位是平方厘米
This table, it's in square centimeters
但是我当成平方米了
I read it as square meters.
你知道这意味着什么吗?
You know what that means?
美国人不擅长公制?
That Americans can't handle the metric system?
Amy 我相差了整整一万倍
Amy, I was off by a factor of 10,000.
可是中国研究队发现了这个元素啊
But the Chinese team found the element.
没错 但他们不该发现的
Yeah, well, they shouldn't have.
我的计算是错的
My calculations were wrong.
这个我生命中伟大的科学成就
The greatest scientific achievement of my life
是基于一个错误
is based on a blunder.
我不是天才
I'm not a genius.
而是个骗子
I'm a fraud.
Sheldon 在神经学里
You know, Sheldon, in neuroscience,
我们总是在意想之外的地方
we're forever finding something in one part of the brain
发现我们要找的东西
that we thought was someplace else.
这下好了 我连骗子都不如
Oh, great, now I'm worse than a fraud.
简直是生物学家了
I'm practically a biologist.
现在...
这里是"科学星期五"节目 我是Ira Flatow
This is Science Friday. I'm Ira Flatow.
今天的嘉宾发现了第一个
My guest today is responsible for the discovery of the first
稳定超重元素
stable super-heavy element.
欢迎做客节目 Sheldon Cooper博士
Welcome, Dr. Sheldon Cooper.
谢谢
Thank you.
是大学让我来的
Uh, the university made me come here.
我可不情愿
I didn't want to.
我很喜欢这档节目
Uh, big fan of the show.
我获悉 你是由一个意外
So, I understand that you actually discovered
才发现了这个元素
this element by mistake.
没错
Yes.
有些科学界的人称之为
And some people in the science community are calling it
"奇妙的错误"
"The Wonder Blunder."
是谁? 告诉我名字
Who? Give me their names.
我猜一定是Wolowitz
I bet it's Wolowitz.
这整件事情太神奇了
It's just such a fascinating story.
你的计算彻底错了
Your calculations are way off,
但他们却找到了元素
but they find the element anyway.
就像是看错了寻宝图
It's like misreading a treasure map
却还是找到了宝藏
and still finding the treasure.
我们能聊聊其它话题吗?
Can we talk about something else?
你知道我会唱约德尔腔吗?
Do you know that I yodel?
(一种乡村唱法)
很有趣 但这件事可能会让你
That's interesting, but this could be taking you
获得诺贝尔奖
down the path toward a Nobel Prize.
不过是化学方面的
And in Chemistry, no less.
难道不是很不寻常吗?
And wouldn't that be unusual?
因为你是个物理学家
Because you're a physicist.
没错 那我就会是一个拿了化学诺贝尔奖的物理学家
Yes, yes, I'd be a physicist with a Nobel in Chemistry.
大家都会嘲笑马戏团的小丑
Everyone laugh at the circus freak.
要知道 我不用坐在这儿被你羞辱的 Flatow
You know, I don't need to sit here and take this, Flatow.
就因为有你这样的混混
It is because of bullies like you,
现在越来越多的美国人
every day more and more Americans
才会放弃广播 转看电视的
are making the switch to television.
* 宇宙一度又烫又稠密 *
* Our whole universe was in a hot, dense state *
* 140亿年前终于爆了炸... 等着瞧! *
* Then nearly 14 billion years ago expansion started... Wait! *
* 地球开始降温 *
* The Earth began to cool *
* 自养生物来起哄 穴居人发明工具 *
* The autotrophs began to drool, Neanderthals developed tools *
* 我们建长城 我们建金字塔 *
* We built the Wall We built the pyramids *
* 数学 自然科学 历史 揭开神秘 *
* Math, Science, History, unraveling the mystery *
* 一切由大爆炸开始 *
* That all started with a big bang *
生活大爆炸 第七季第十集
--==圣城家园SCG字幕组 http://hd.cnscg.com/==--
仅供翻译交流使用, 禁止用于商业用途
协调：初见
时间轴：pisces夜
翻译：酱油影 Julie wanna307 波特妹子 笑点滴 初见 UU坚持住
校对：UU坚持住
Seibert校长 我不知道你干嘛要大吼大叫
President Seibert, I don't know why you're yelling.
是你让我去接受电台访谈的
You're the one who made me go on the radio.
我本来以为是专业的科学采访
I was expecting a professional science interview,
不是这种攻击人为乐的无脑节目
not an attack by some morning zoo shock jock.
如果学校这么需要钱的话
Well, if the university needs money so badly,
你不如搞个脏话罐
perhaps you should start a swear jar.
哇哦! 这句就得罚一美元
Whoa! That one's worth a dollar.
我知道你不喜欢做采访
I know you don't like it,
但每次你接受采访
but every time you do an interview,
学校曝光率就高一点
it raises the profile of the university.
筹款就多一些
That translates to funding.
但我不是被耍的猴啊
Yeah, well, I'm not just
为赚硬币而跳舞
some trained monkey dancing for coins.
你当然不是
Of course you're not.
人们至少喜欢猴子
People love trained monkeys.
你怎么能不开心呢?
How can you not be happy?
你又高 又瘦 又有名
You're tall, thin and famous.
天啊 我嫉妒Sheldon
Oh, my God, I'm jealous of Sheldon.
反正像这样的事情还得再继续
Look, you're gonna be doing this stuff for a while.
你不如找到一种方式来适应它
You're just gonna have to find a way to get used to it.
但你们都不知道那是什么滋味
But none of you know what this is like.
因为一件你后悔的事而被祝贺
Being celebrated for something you wish you never did.
嗯... 看来你没跟我一起过狂欢节
Mmm... you clearly haven't been with me at Mardi Gras.
想不想停下游戏 帮我收拾?
Want to pause the video game and help me clean up?
我在收拾呢
I am cleaning up.
看看小丑把哥谭市祸害成什么样了
Look at the mess the Joker made of Gotham City.
拜托 要来住的是你朋友
Come on, it's your friend who's coming to stay here.
Raj是在印度长大的
Raj grew up in India.
他见过更脏的地方 相信我
Trust me, he's seen worse.
Howie啊
Howie.
我保证
I promise I'll help out
这周我都会帮忙的
the rest of the week.
这周?
The rest of the week?
你说他只住一两晚
You said it was just gonna be a night or two.
是 但如果我跟你说一周
Yeah, but if I told you a week,
你会答应吗?
would you have said yes?
- 不会!  - 对啊 我别无选择嘛
- No!  - Then you left me no choice.
我喜欢Raj 但作为客人 他要住的也太久了
I love Raj, but that's a long time for a house guest.
但他们在补他的房子呢
I know, but they're tenting his building.
他找不到可以带狗入住的旅馆
He can't find a hotel he likes that allows dogs.
他要带Cinnamon来?
He's bringing Cinnamon?
住一周!
For a whole week!
有些人的胆子可真是不小啊
The nerve of some people.
驶来的是耻辱号
Here comes the Embarrassment Express.
将停靠在卑鄙骗子村...
With stops at Fraudville...
大错特错镇...
WonderBlunderberg...
和堪萨斯市
and Kansas City.
因为那是交通枢纽
Because it's a hub.
Sheldon 我能进来吗?
Sheldon, can I come in?
- 你有饼干吗?  - 没有
- Do you have cookies?  - No.
好 我也不配吃饼干 进来吧
Good. I don't deserve cookies. Come in.
Wil你...?
Wil...?
嘿 Sheldon
Hey, Sheldon.
好久不见啊
It's been a while.
你怎么来了?
Why are you here?
Amy说你最近不太开心
Amy said you were having a rough time,
所以我想我们可以聊聊
and I thought maybe we could talk.
可以吗?
Is that okay?
当然
Certainly.
尽管...
Although...
有三个人在我的房间里
right now, I'm having a rough time
所以现在我不太开心
because there's three people in my room,
我感觉有点像在迪斯科舞厅里
and it's starting to feel like a discotheque.
Sheldon 你说你不希望因为自己后悔的事
Sheldon, you said you were unhappy getting attention
而得到关注
for something you wished you never did.
是 我有点理解那种感觉
Yeah, I know a little something about that.
胡说 Wil
Oh, nonsense, Wil.
你没完没了的发推特也没那么讨厌
Your endless tweets are not that bad.
我知道我们为什么这么久没见了
I remember why it's been a while.
Sheldon 其实我想说的是
Sheldon, I was actually talking
我小时候 演星际迷航的时候
about when I was a kid on Star Trek.
你演的是Wesley Crusher
How could you not like getting attention
怎么会不喜欢被关注呢?
for playing Wesley Crusher?
你演的太棒了
You were wonderful.
一个过目不忘而且无所不知的天才男孩
A know-it-all boy genius with an eidetic memory.
谁看了都会觉得你把他们自己给演出来了
Who couldn't relate to that?
呃 并不是所有人都这么想
Well, not everybody felt that way.
很多人讨厌我的角色
A lot of people really hated the character,
有些人连带着也讨厌起我来
and some of them hated me because of it.
我参加采访的时候
I would do interviews,
人们对我的态度很不好
and people would be mean to me.
我就是这么被欺负的
That just happened to me.
下一次你想不出推特发什么好的时候
Next time you're stuck for a tweet,
就说Ira Flatow是个混蛋
feel free to say what a jerk Ira Flatow is.
Sheldon 重点是Wil学会了怎么接受
Sheldon, the point is Wil learned to embrace
他那段不愉快的生活 然后继续向更大更高的目标努力
that part of his life and moved on to bigger and better things.
是啊 我现在是作家了
Yeah, I'm an author now,
我给公众演讲
I do public speaking,
而且我自己还制作了有关棋牌游戏的网络剧
and I have my own Web series about board games.
呃...
Uh...
我们现在是给Sheldon鼓劲 所以...
We're trying to cheer him up, so...
我的意思是曾经有一段时间
I'm just saying that there was a time
我认为我爬不出Wesley Crusher的阴影了
when I thought I would never get out of Wesley Crusher's shadow.
但是现在我明白
But now,
那段经历只是我精彩生活的一小部分
it's just one small part of a pretty great life,
而且我很高兴我拥有了那样一段经历
and it's a part that I'm happy is there.
我明白你的意思
I do see what you're saying.
对我很有帮助
That helps.
那就好
Good.
你们俩愿意留下来
Would you two like to stay
跟我一起玩火车吗?
and play trains with me?
- 没问题  - 好的
- Sure.  - Okay.
噢 太好了!
Oh, great!
现在...
Now...
我来控制火车
I work the controls.
我来说"各位请上车"
I say "All aboard."
你们安静地坐在那看着就好
You sit quietly and watch.
我能给火车鸣笛吗?
Can I blow the whistle?
那你还是走吧
You should probably go.
你要在我的沙发上刷牙?
You're gonna brush your teeth on my couch?
不是啊 我要给Cinnamon刷牙
No, I'm gonna brush Cinnamon's teeth.
干嘛给狗刷牙啊?
Why bother?
她每天花一半的时间
She spends half the time
在舔屁股
licking her butt.
那另一半时间都在舔我的脸啊
And the other half licking my face.
所以我才要给她刷牙
That's why I'm brushing her teeth.
嗨 不好意思我回来晚了
Hey, guys. Sorry I'm so late.
你们已经吃过晚饭了吗?
Did you already have dinner?
没呢 我们在等你回来
No, we were waiting for you.
哦 真体贴
Aw, that's so sweet.
那是 你晚饭打算做什么?
Yeah. So what do you feel like making?
Howard怎么说话的 小可怜
Howard, the poor thing
刚刚才下班回家
just got home from work.
让我给你倒一杯酒吧
Let me get you a glass of wine.
我来做饭
I'll cook dinner.
- 噢 Raj 那怎么行 你是我们的客人啊  - 不要客气了
- Oh, Raj, you're our guest.  - Don't be silly.
坐下来 看样子你忙了一整天
Sit. You look like you've had a long day.
才不是呢 她每天都是这副样子
No, she always looks like that.
因为她嫁了一个傻子
Because she married an idiot.
谢谢你 Raj
Thank you, Raj.
不用这么客气
Please, this is
这是我答谢你们的方式
my way of thanking you
你们都让我住家里了
for letting me stay here.
跟我们说说你今天都干了什么
Now, tell us all about your day.
好的 呃 首先
Okay, um, well, first,
我开会迟到了 因为路上太堵
I was late to a meeting 'cause I was stuck in traffic.
难怪 我跟你说了多少次 把那个路况软件安在手机上
Well, I keep telling you to put that traffic app on your phone.
嘿 当你今天回到家的时候 你跟我抱怨说
Hey, when you got home today complaining that you felt sick
你吃了太多的软糖 肚子难受
from eating too many jelly beans,
我有没有说你不应该吃那么多糖?
did I tell you how to fix it?
没有
No.
我说的是 "哦 很难受吧" 然后我帮你摸摸肚子
I said, "Aw, that must hurt," and I rubbed your belly.
我可是一直想着你的
I thought of you the whole time.
我说的意思是有时候要善于倾听
All I'm saying is there's a time to just listen.
谢谢
Thank you.
而且有些时候
There's also a time to stop
就不要吃那么多软糖了
eating too many jelly beans.
比如十岁以后
And it's when you're ten.
你好 Siebert校长
Hello, President Siebert.
谢谢您接我电话
Thank you for taking my call.
我只是想告诉你现在
I just wanted you to know that you can now expect
我对自己的科学发现会非常积极
enthusiastic participation from me regarding my discovery.
哦 不不
Oh, no, no, no, no.
不需要谢我
No need to thank me.
谢我的朋友 Wil Wheaton
Thank my friend, Wil Wheaton.
不怕告诉您 我有九个朋友 怎样?
For your information, I have nine friends, hmm?
加上你算十个
Ten if we include you.
那还是九个
Nine it is.
啊 是十个
Ah, it's ten.
Wolowitz也算
I'll count Wolowitz.
你好 我的朋友Leonard
Hello, friend Leonard.
嘿 你心情不错啊
Hey, you're in a good mood.
是心情大好
I'm in a great mood.
接下来你会心情更好的
Well, you're about to be in an even better one.
在不确定之前
I didn't want to say anything
我不想说什么 但是...
until I knew for sure, but...
我一直在实验室重现你的元素实验
I've been re-running the tests on your element in my lab
然后推翻了它
and I disproved it.
你的元素是不存在的!
Your element does not exist!
但中国研究队是怎么回事?
Yeah, but what about the Chinese research team?
他们找到了
They found it.
原来是有人向数据文件里
Yeah, it turns out someone added
掺了仿真信号
simulated signals to the data files.
他们伪造了结果
They faked the results.
真的?
Really?
没错! 你知道这意味着什么吗?
Yes! Do you know what that means?
意味着你痛恨的这些关注都会烟消云散了
That means all of this attention that you hate goes away.
所以不会有采访了?
So no more interviews?
没了 都结束了
No, it's all over.
简直不敢相信
I can't believe it.
不用客气
Well, you're welcome.
你抢走了
You robbed me
我最大的成就!
of my greatest achievement!
什么?!
What?!
我现在只有九个朋友了!
I'm back down to nine friends!
是八个... 我也讨厌Wolowitz!
Make it eight... I'm sick of Wolowitz, too!
我不明白
I... I don't understand.
自从发现这愚蠢的元素后
All you've done since you discovered
你就一直在抱怨
this stupid element was complain.
我是想让你开心!
I was trying to make you happy!
所以夺走我唯一成名的机会吗?
By taking away my only claim to fame?
如果你想让我开心
Well, if you wanted to make me happy,
你可以给我讲个笑话
you could have told me a joke.
或者给我看一个萌视频
Or shown me a cute video
里面考拉和水獭
of a koala and an otter
不可思议的变成了好朋友
becoming unlikely friends.
跟你就没好果子吃
Oh, there is no winning with you.
而且考拉和水獭都不住在一起!
And koalas and otters don't even live near each other!
所以说它们的友谊不可思议!
That's what makes their friendship unlikely!
嘿!
Hey!
吵什么呢?
What's with all the yelling?
Leonard证明了我的元素不存在
Leonard disproved my element.
现在所有的关注都不会有了
Now all the attention is going to go away.
太棒了 你肯定激动坏了!
Oh, that's great. You must be thrilled!
够了! 我只有七个朋友了
That's it! I'm down to seven friends.
他加上了霍比特人和超级英雄 对吧?
He's counting Hobbits and superheroes, right?
当我以为元素存在的时候 我不想要它
When I thought the element was real, I didn't want it.
但现在Leonard让它不存在了
But now that Leonard made it not exist,
我比世界上任何事都想要它
I want it more than anything in the world.
元素本来就不存在的
The... the element never existed.
不是我夺走的 是科学夺走的
I didn't take it away, science took it away.
生科学的气啊
Be mad at science.
不许用科学来对付我
Don't you dare use science against me.
科学是我最好的朋友!
Science is my best friend!
太好了 我又有八个朋友了
Oh, good, I'm back up to eight.
你能告诉他他精神失常了吗
Will you tell him he's out of his mind.
其实 我懂他的意思
Actually, I get what he's saying.
太棒了! 九个朋友!
Oh, yes! Nine!
欢迎归队 伙计
Welcome back, buddy.
就像你和你不爱的人恋爱
It's like if you're dating someone you're not that into,
然后和分手了
and then they break up with you,
最后发现你又想要他了
and then you want them more than ever.
我不知道她在说什么
I have no idea what she's talking about,
但我们是一伙的 所以我同意
but we're ganged up on you so I agree.
好吧 Sheldon 你想让我怎样
Okay, Sheldon, what do you want me to do,
把信息藏起来吗?
hide the information?
如果我不发表
If I don't publish it,
肯定别人会发表 只是时间的问题
it's just a matter of time before someone else does.
不 不 你当然要发表
No, no, of course you have to publish.
那是你身为科学家的职责
That's your responsibility as a scientist.
要不然就没有职业操守了
Doing otherwise would be unethical.
你毫无选择
You have no choice.
好吧 我发表
Fine, I'll publish.
你能相信他吗?
Can you believe this guy?
哇! Raj洗碗啦
Aw! Raj did the dishes.
你怎么不说是我洗的?
How do you know I didn't do them?
因为有一次 所有刀具都脏的时候
Because once, when all the knives were dirty,
你用钥匙隔开了一个面包圈
you cut a bagel with your keys.
大家早上好哇
Good morning, everybody.
我出去给大家买了咖啡哟
I picked up coffee while I was out.
Bernadette 这是你的大豆薄荷摩卡
Bernadette, here's your soy peppermint mocha.
太谢谢你了
Aw, you didn't have to do that.
没事 别为你的报告
Oh, my pleasure, and don't worry
而担忧哦
about your presentation today.
你会表现很好的
You're gonna be great.
是啊 你会大获成功的
Yeah, you're gonna knock it out of the park.
我今天的报告是什么?
What presentation do I have today?
快去吧
Just go.
他是爱你哒
He loves you.
你在干嘛?
What are you doing?
想让我难堪吗?
Are you trying to make me look bad?
我只是想当个好客人嘛
I'm just being a good house guest.
哪有 你当了比我更好的老公
No, you're being a better husband than I am.
又是洗碗 又是买咖啡
Doing the dishes, getting coffee,
还了解她的生活...
knowing about her life...
这都是谁干的?
Who does that?
得了吧 我也给你买了啊
Oh, come on, I brought you one, too.
我不想喝咖啡
I don't want coffee.
所以我给你买了热可可
That's why I got you hot chocolate.
给我吧
Give me that.
别让我难堪了
Just stop showing me up.
Howard 听着
Howard, listen to me.
你是一个好丈夫
You're a great husband.
你的听话技巧要加强了
Yes, your listening skills could use some work.
但你已经很不错了
But it's amazing how far you've come given that you're
作为一个有过度保护欲的妈妈的独子
an only child raised by an over-protective mom.
这发展好像不太对劲?
Um, is this getting weird?
等一下
Hang on.
是很奇怪
So, yes.
嘿
Hey.
我只是来告诉你 我...我把研究成果发出去了
I just wanted to let you know that I... I posted my findings.
我看到了
I saw.
我也刚把
And I just
我的论文撤回了
posted a retraction of my paper.
现在所有科学界的人都知道我错了
Now the whole scientific community knows I was wrong.
这种事常发生 Sheldon
These things happen all the time, Sheldon.
对我来说不然
Not to me.
仅有一次的撤回是
The only other retraction I ever had to issue
我七岁那年承认我哥是德州东部
was when I was seven and I conceded that my brother
最伟大的忍者
was the greatest ninja in East Texas.
因为我的脸被他的腋窝夹住了
But that was just a ploy to get my face out of his armpit.
你在这啊!
There he is!
我最爱的超级英雄...
It's my favorite superhero...
撤回侠!
the Retractor!
好了 别让他难堪
Come on, don't give him a hard time.
不好意思 Cooper
I'm sorry, Cooper.
我撤回刚才说的
I retract it.
随便提一下 Hofstadter
By the way, Hofstadter,
推翻中国研究队这件事干的不错
nice job disproving the Chinese team.
没什么
It's not a big deal.
当然有什么了
It's a huge deal.
Cooper 也许你不是研究物理的料
Cooper, maybe physics just isn't your thing.
你考虑过去零售业吗?
Have you ever considered a career in retail?
那样还能偷偷拿点吃的回家
That way you could take things back for a living.
好了 Barry 别说了
Okay, Barry, that's enough.
哦 没关系
Oh, no, that's okay.
我能应付的过来
I can fight my own battles.
你说对吧 Bawwy
Isn't that right, "Bawwy."
(讽刺他r和w不分)
你...?
Is...?
你这是在讽刺我话说不清吗?
Is that a reference to my speech impediment?
太伤人了
That's pretty hurtful.
我...
I...
我又不想那样
I can't control it.
你说得对
You're right,
我过分了
That was uncalled for.
我收回那句话
I take it back.
你当然要收回了
Of course you do.
因为你是撤回侠!
Because you're the Retractor!
Raj 晚餐太美味了
Raj, this dinner was amazing.
如果你多住几天
If you're here much longer,
我都得买大一号的衣服了
I'm gonna have to buy bigger clothes.
怎么会
Nonsense.
你应该长点肉
You need a little fattening up.
你最近太瘦了
You've been looking too skinny lately.
啊
Aw.
Howie 你怎么就不能像人家那样会说话?
Howie, how come you never say anything sweet like that?
怎么回事?
What are you talking about?
还记得上周吗? 我以为
Remember last week, when I asked you
你穿了紧身裤但你没穿
if you were wearing Spanx and you weren't?
我怎么不会说话了?
How's that different?
也许你可以学学你朋友Raj那样
Maybe you could try being more thoughtful,
更体贴一点
like your friend Raj.
哦 好吧 也许你该像Raj学学
Yeah, well, maybe you could try being more like Raj.
哦 是吗?
Oh, really?
嗯 嗯
Yeah, yeah.
今天早上他给我带了爱心便当
He packed me a lunch this morning.
里面还有一张字条 写着"加油哟"
And there was a note inside that said, "Go get 'em."
你这么说 像我做的不够多似的
Like I don't do enough around here.
还要我给你做便当?
Now I need to pack your lunch?
再说了 你是成年人了!
And by the way, why do you need a note telling you
还要写着"加油哟"的字条干嘛!
to "go get 'em"? You're a grown man!
你自己应该知道"加油"的!
You should know to "go get 'em"!
我知道要"加油"
I do know to "go get 'em,"
但在我加油的时候
but sometimes it's nice to have emotional support
能得到一点鼓励更好!
when I'm going and getting them!
嘿 嘿 你们说什么呢?
Hey, hey, do you hear yourselves?
都冷静一下 各让一步吧
Let's just, you know, all calm down and take a step back.
太傻了
This is stupid.
我们为什么要吵架?
Why are we fighting?
不知道
I don't know.
我就是觉得
I guess I was just feeling
我是个坏丈夫
like I'm a lousy husband.
你才不是坏丈夫
You're not a lousy husband.
你是个好丈夫
You're a great husband.
我才是讨厌的妻子
I was the one feeling like a lousy wife.
说什么呢? 你是最好的妻子
Are you kidding? You're the best.
我知道问题所在了
I know what the problem is.
都怪他!
It's him!
哦 我做什么了?
Oh, what did I do?
你想挑拨我们俩
You made us feel like we're not trying hard enough.
嗯 我们正努力磨合婚姻
Yeah, we were totally fine half-assing our marriage
但你一出现就都乱了
till you showed up.
听着 很抱歉惹你们生气了
Look, I'm sorry you're upset with me,
但我只是想说 我很开心
but I just have to say it's nice to see
你们俩终于一条战线了
the two of you on the same page.
哦 有你支持我
Oh, it does feel good
我真是太开心了
to have you backing me up for once.
我一直都很支持你!
I back you up all the time!
不对... 他又来了! 你怎么回事?!
That is not... he's doing it again! What is wrong with you?!
他们竟然把你赶出来了
I can't believe they kicked you out.
他俩竟然还没离婚
I can't believe they're still married.
哦 不 我把Cinnamon的牙刷落在Howard家了
Oh, no, I forgot Cinnamon's toothbrush at Howard's.
那你就和爹地用一把吧
I guess you're sharing with Daddy again.
你嗷一声我就帮你联系善待动物组织
Bark once if you need me to call PETA.
咱公寓里怎么多了个这货
What's that animal doing in our apartment?
没事的 她在笼子里跑不出来
Oh, relax, she's in her crate. She can't get out.
我提醒你一下
I have two words for you:
(恐龙冲出围栏)
侏罗纪公园
Jurassic Park.
今天真是越来越糟了
This day just keeps getting worse and worse.
如果能让你稍微高兴点...
You know, if it makes you feel any better...
应该不会的
It probably won't.
你说得对
You're probably right.
Sheldon 夜色如此美好
Sheldon, it's a beautiful night.
咱俩要不去散散步
Why don't you and I go for a nice walk together?
你怎么随时随地都想那档子事啊
Oh, everything is just sex with you isn't it?
Sheldon 我觉得如果你能认识到
Sheldon, I think you might find the support
恋爱中有付出也有回报
you're looking for, if you realize
你就会得到想要的支持
that relationships are a give and take.
你给她一个拥抱
She can only be there for you
她才会还你一个港湾
as much as you are for her.
多谢 Rajesh
Thank you, Rajesh.
Amy 你也得耐心对待Sheldon
And, Amy, you need to be patient with Sheldon,
不要总逼着他跟你进行亲密接触
instead of pressuring him to accept intimacy on your terms.
你还是走吧
You should probably go.
我是Ira Flatow 现在您收听的是科学星期五
I'm Ira Flatow, and this is Science Friday.
首先欢迎Sheldon Cooper博士的回归
I'd like to welcome back Dr. Sheldon Cooper,
他以为自己发现了
who thought he had discovered
一种新的超重元素 却被下一位来宾推翻
a new super-heavy element only to have it disproved
那就是Leonard Hofstadter博士
by my next guest, Dr. Leonard Hofstadter.
您好 欢迎来到科学星期五
Welcome to Science Friday, gentlemen.
- 谢谢  - 谢谢
- Thanks.  - Thank you.
Ira 你不介意的话
Ira, if I may, I'd like to apologize
我想为上周道个歉
for my behavior last week.
没关系
It's all right.
那 你有没有什么要对我说的?
Now, isn't there something you'd like to say to me?
没
No.
Hofstadter博士
Now, Dr. Hofstadter.
你能不能跟我们讲讲
Can you walk us through the process
你是如何推翻他的结论的?
you used to disprove his theory?
这个... 我可以回答
Well... I believe I can answer that.
他问的是我
He asked me.
好吧
Fine.
正如我说的...
As I was saying...
你说错了 Ira...
You're telling it wrong. Ira...
这件事要说个明白
to really understand the story here,
我得从头说起
you have to start at the very beginning:
在德州东边的一个小镇上 一位少年天才...
A small town in East Texas, where a young genius named...
- Sheldon...  - 对 他叫Sheldon Cooper
- Sheldon...  - That's right, Sheldon Cooper.
他被领居家的狗咬伤了
He was bitten by his neighbor's dog,
激发他做出了他人生中第一个科学成果...
leading to his first scientific breakthrough...
狗狗死亡射线
the doggie death-ray.
但因为圣诞老人给不了浓缩铀
Which, sadly, he couldn't build
这个成果没能实现
because Santa wouldn't bring him enriched uranium.
我比较想听Hofstadter博士来说
I mean, I'd really like to hear it from Dr. Hofstadter,
如果你不介意的话
if it's okay with you.
真奇怪
What a surprise.
你... 请我过来就是无视我的吗?
Did... did you invite me back just so you could ignore me?
其实 我也没请你吧
Actually, I didn't invite you.
你就这么走进来坐下了
You came in, you took a seat,
我也不想跟你对质
and I'm not comfortable with confrontation.
Sheldon 这是对我的采访
Sheldon, this interview is supposed to be about me.
无趣得我都要打哈欠了
Well, that seems like a snooze.
虽说是广播电台节目吧
Even for public radio.
如果每次他们说些丢人的话
You know, if we did a shot every time
我们就喝一杯
they said something embarrassing,
那我们肯定喝嗨了
this would be one hell of a drinking game.
现在喝酒太早了吧
A little early for alcohol, isn't it?
我不止在科学上颇有建树
You know, I don't just say smart things about science.
我还会约德尔腔
I also yodel.
我去拿伏特加
I'll get the vodka.
--==圣城家园SCG字幕组 http://hd.cnscg.com/==--
仅供翻译交流使用, 禁止用于商业用途
协调：初见
时间轴：pisces夜
翻译：酱油影 Julie wanna307 波特妹子 笑点滴 初见 UU坚持住
校对：UU坚持住